Lewend Mayiwar

Oslo, Norway — lewend.mayiwar@bi.no — lewendmayiwar.com

Research overview

My PhD project aims to explore the role of emotions and emotion regulation in decisions involving risk. The goal of the research is to understand how people regulate their emotions and how this impacts their physiological responses, information processing, and ultimately, their decisions.

To answer these questions, I mainly rely on controlled experiments (both laboratory experiments and online experiments). In the lab we employ a variety of novel tools that allows us to gain rich insight into underlying emotional and cognitive processes. These include physiological instruments that measure skin conductance and heart rate variability, eye-tracking, and virtual reality headsets.

My overall approach to research is guided by an interest in open science practices and reproducibility.

EMPLOYMENT & RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

PhD Candidate 2019 - present

Supervised research, BI Norwegian Business School

Conducting experiments to understand the impact of emotion regulation on

decisions, physiology, and information processing.

2018 - 2019 Department of Leadership and Organizational Behavior, BI Norwegian **Business School**

Research Assistant: I worked in two projects, where I was tasked with handling large data sets, matching responses from different surveys, restructuring data for multilevel modeling, cleaning data/pre-processing. In the first project, I assisted in setting up the longitudinal experiment and designing a growth mindset intervention, coordinating with members across departments at campus in order to successfully run this school-wide project, setting up and distributing the survey, analyzing and reporting data, and participated in meetings to update members on the status of the project. In addition, I worked in another large-scale project investigating organizational reform in the Norwegian police.

2016 - 2018 LearningLab, BI Norwegian Business School

Help Desk Assistant: Primarily involved with facilitating and supporting digital pedagogy practices on campus for faculty and staff.

2018 Department of Leadership and Organizational Behavior, BI Norwegian **Business School**

Research Assistant: supervising the research lab, such as running human subjects

through experimental procedures involving computer-based tasks.

2017 - 2018 Department of Leadership and Organizational Behavior, BI Norwegian **Business School**

Research Assistant: Tasked with reviewing, identifying, and summarizing Norwegian Laws relevant to diversity and equality in the work place and summarizing statistics on Norwegian equality and diversity.

2017 **BI Norwegian Business School**

Tel: +47 922 188 68 Lewend Mayiwar E-mail: lewend.mayiwar@bi.no Teaching Assistant: Facilitated Norwegian-speaking first-year bachelor students' academic success and assisted with initial adjustment to their university academic life. I was primarily involved with holding extra sessions on campus to aid students in their course work.

2016 - present Institute for Research & Development in Kurdistan

External Consultant: Consulting on methodological and analytical tools related to

research.

Vialina AB, Västerås

Telemarketer: Customer service

EDUCATION

2016 - 2018 Master of Science in Leadership & Organizational Psychology

BI Norwegian Business School, Oslo, Norway

Master thesis: "Noise and Cognitive Flexibility: Exploring the Moderating Role of Mindfulness, and the Mediating Mechanisms of Arousal and Cognitive Processing."

2013 - 2016 Bachelor of Science in Business and Economics

Mälardalens University, Västerås, Sweden

Bachelor thesis: "The Process of Retaining Knowledge: A Case Study of PwC."

PUBLICATIONS

Mayiwar, L. & Lai, L. (2019). Replication of Study 1 in 'Differentiating Social and Personal Power:
 Opposite Effects on Stereotyping, but Parallel Effects on Behavioral Approach Tendencies' by
 Lammers, Stoker, and Stapel (2009). Manuscript accepted for publication in the journal of Social
 Psychology. [Peer-reviewed]

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

 Mayiwar, L. (2020, May). Psychological Distance & Risk Seeking: Unpacking Emotional and Cognitive Mechanisms. Talk presented at the Distances in Organizations Workshop, McGill University, Montreal, Canada.

COURSES TAUGHT

• Judgment and Decision Making in Organizations: MSc course.

UNIVERSITY AND PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

 Co-organizer of ReproducibiliTea BI Oslo, an open science journal club dedicated to raising awareness of open science and reproducibility

RESEARCH SKILLS

- Basic statistics: descriptives, t-tests, correlation, regression, graphs
- Intermediate statistics: ANOVA
- Advanced statistics: mediation and moderation (using Hayes' PROCESS macro), some basic
 experience in multilevel modelling (mostly in preparing data sets for multilevel analysis), and
 exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis.

Lewend Mayiwar Tel: +47 922 188 68

- Measurement of physiological arousal, through Skin Conductance Response (SCR).
- Statistical softwares: RStudio, SPSS, JAMOVI

SERVICE TO PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

2017 - 2018 Scandinavian Journal of Organizational Psychology

Member of the Editorial Board, Associate Editor

Published articles are presented in the Publications list above. Besides writing articles for the journal, I was also responsible for reviewing other fellow members' articles, and participating in meetings with the chief editor to decide on a theme for each issue.

2017 - 2018 Norsk Organisasjonspsykologisk Selskap (NOS)

Member of the Board. Involved with the management of the journal. Acting as an ambassador for the journal, tasks included sourcing potential authors and readers and also potential subscribers.

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

Swedish
 English
 Fluent, reading and writing. I use Swedish daily at work and home.
 English
 Fluent, reading and writing. Preferred in academic reading and writing.

• Kurdish Native, good command in reading and writing

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Academy of Management
 Divisions: Managerial and Organizational Cognition, Organizational Behavior, Research Methods

 Society for Judgment and Decision Making www.sjdm.org

Lewend Mayiwar Tel: +47 922 188 68